# Alis Mangukiya

Canada | +1 782 778 6486 | alismangukiya1011@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

AWS certified Full Stack Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in optimizing UIs, microservices, and database performance. Proficient in JavaScript, Java, Angular, React, NodeJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS and Cloud technologies. Ready to drive innovation and exceed expectations.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages:JavaScript, Java, Python, SQL, C/C++Frameworks:Angular, NodeJS, Express, CypressWWW TechnologiesHTML, JSON, REST API's, CSS, JQueryLibraries:React, Redux, React Router, Bootstrap

**Methodologies:** Agile, SDLC, SOLID, TDD

Cloud Services: Amazon web services, Microsoft Azure, Google cloud platform SQL Server, Oracle DB, MongoDB, MySQL, DynamoDB

**Tools:** Git, Kubernetes, Docker, Jira, Postman, Jenkins

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Full stack developer co-op | Nova Scotia Health Authority

September 2023 – December 2023

Technologies: Angular, Typescript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Git, Agile, Microsoft Azure cloud

- Spearheaded the development of real-time patient flow and wait time dashboards for emergency department waiting rooms in Nova Scotia hospitals, utilizing Angular.
- Actively contributing to the creation of an automated surgery scheduling tool leveraging Angular, Express, and NodeJS, optimizing scheduling procedures based on priority through data analytics and machine learning.
- Utilizing Spark for training models to predict emergency department wait times and efficiently schedule surgeries, thereby improving resource allocation and enhancing overall patient care.
- Proficiently applied the agile methodology to ensure seamless task tracking and efficient issue management, fostering a collaborative and proactive team environment.

### Full stack developer | Accenture

January 2021 – August 2022

Technologies: JavaScript, Java, TypeScript, Angular, React, JQuery, Git, Jira, AWS

- Responsible for design, implementation, and maintenance of core product features using JavaScript, Java, TypeScript, Angular8+, and ReactJS.
- Effectively managed and orchestrated the requirements within the developers and other teams to enhance and improve the overall requirements, functionality, and user experience.
- Led brainstorming and foundations for the product design and architecture.
- Actively participated in troubleshooting and presenting the root cause analysis to the stakeholders along with the solutions or workarounds to reduce impact and blockers.
- Organized and delivered client feature walkthroughs, demos, support, and training for seamless and effective adoption of the product.

### Full stack development Intern | CYGNUX Softtech Pvt. Ltd

September 2020 – December 2020

Technologies: React, MongoDB, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Git, Jira

- Worked in a team environment to design, develop, and maintain web applications using React, MongoDB, Express and NodeJS.
- Collaborated with other developers, UI/UX designers, and project managers to ensure that projects were completed on time and meet client requirements.
- Used JIRA for task tracking, issue management, and project reporting helping to keep projects organized.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Applied Computer Science | GPA: 3.94/4.30 Dalhousie University | Halifax, NS, Canada

### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

## Multi-Cloud Trivia Game | AWS, GCP, React, Serverless, CloudFormation, Git, Jira | GitHub

The project was a real-time trivia game entirely designed and deployed using serverless framework and resources on cloud platforms AWS and GCP. I was responsible for the designing, implementation, and integration of user authorization and authentication along with Chatbot functionalities.

#### DesigniteJava – IntelliJ IDE Plugin | Java, Spring, Jira, TDD, Git | GitHub | DesigniteJava

Project on open-source contribution to JetBrains plugin DesigniteJava which involves identifying the various types of code smells, analytics, suggestions on fixing the code smell, and reporting for code quality and metrics.

#### Reboundr | NodeJS, ReactJS, REST API, MongoDB, Git, Jira | GitHub

Developed a MERN stack application enabling smooth job seeker-employer collaboration. Managed user authentication, streamlined profiles, and integrated networking features. Implemented an intuitive UX design. Deployed on Netlify (front-end) and Render (back-end), utilizing Git for version control.

#### **AWARDS & ACHIVEMENTS**

- Authored an open-source contribution to <u>DesigniteJava</u> which is now live with approximately 4.K downloads.
- Volunteer Work Worked for vlife as UI and UX tester to support and grow local businesses.

## **CERTIFICATES**

**AWS Certified Developer - Associate**